<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consultant on Recency Bias</title>
    <link>http://badu.github.io/tags/consultant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consultant on Recency Bias</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://badu.github.io/tags/consultant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with me</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/hire-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/hire-me/</guid>
      <description>Working with Bogdan (Badu) I&amp;rsquo;m wearing many hats, having a non trivial understanding of human resources, software development process, risk management, diplomacy and engineering. Nowadays I write tools in Go, web applications and automate stuff. I deal with data stores, schedulers, security, etc. and I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to improve things.
What I will bring to the table  Excellent communication and technical skills Experience with customer-facing activities Experience with software engineering best practices (unit testing, code reviews, design documentation, methodologies) The confidence to input into architecture discussions around deployment topologies, scaling, performance and sizing Many years of experience on building complex systems  What you should bring to the table  Willing to work with remote consultants You should be an agent of change The best possible software and hardware available Use an Agile like software development methodology A competitive package, including flexible hours and unlimited paid holiday  Please feel free to contact me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>