<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on Recency Bias</title>
    <link>http://badu.github.io/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on Recency Bias</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://badu.github.io/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What you can&#39;t do with reflect</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/what-you-cant-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/what-you-cant-do/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the problem? A while ago, I was working on backend application in which we were trying to increase readability of the code, while defining a standard. In my morning explorations I&amp;rsquo;ve found a technique (sorry, can&amp;rsquo;t remember where : I&amp;rsquo;ll edit this article when I&amp;rsquo;ll remember) that allowed us to use reflection inside a before type handler, thus decoding JSON payloads would be agnostic to controllers.
A typical controller signature looks like this :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirror Mirror on ...</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/mirror-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/mirror-mirror/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR While I was mentoring, I encouraged my pupils to break things so they understand how they work. Using reflect package seems easy, but understanding the mechanics is hard. So, this week, following my own advice, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to create my own reflect package. Here is what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
Playing with Fire Most of the articles on the subject I&amp;rsquo;ve read have (more or less) the following advice : &amp;ldquo;if you find yourself doing this in a real program, stop immediately and seek help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing when the world stops</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/known-world-stops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/known-world-stops/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I took the time searching for patterns inside the main packages. Besides a bunch of aha moments, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that some neat tricks can be used to achieve some goals otherwise achievable by applying different techniques.
For instance, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a pool or a cache. How do you call your cleanup function?
Decisions regarding where to place that call can be made by testing and benchmarking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Radix Story</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/radix-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/radix-story/</guid>
      <description>A Radix Story Yes, All You Need is Standard &amp;ldquo;net/http&amp;rdquo; There are, out there in the wild, an abundance of routers that a developer can use. In my opinion, one thing that they all share is the lack of separation of concerns. By separation of concerns I mean mixing handlers with routes and conditions, putting on top of that some cool optimized algorithm for looking up a route (or maybe I should say inspecting a string&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On Net/Http Package - Week 2</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/net-http-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/net-http-week2/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR This series is about my questions and thoughts regarding net/http package. The process of learning is based on mistakes, therefor I&amp;rsquo;m inviting you to learn aside me.
You are allowed to judge the code. You are not allowed to judge the people.
Part 1
ListenAndServe As you might well know, using http package is easy :
package main import ( &amp;quot;io&amp;quot; &amp;quot;net/http&amp;quot; &amp;quot;log&amp;quot; ) func main() { http.HandleFunc(&amp;quot;/hello&amp;quot;, func (w http.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts On Net/Http Package - Week 1</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/net-http-week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/net-http-week1/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR This series is about my questions and thoughts regarding net/http package. The process of learning is based on mistakes, therefor I&amp;rsquo;m inviting you to learn aside me.
You are allowed to judge the code. You are not allowed to judge the people.
First Glance I have a confession to make : despite the fact that &amp;ldquo;Keep types close&amp;rdquo; rule is fair enough, the architect in me needs to reorganize the code in such a manner that a 10000 feet view to be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Go with Other Languages is Wrong</title>
      <link>http://badu.github.io/post/comparing-go-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://badu.github.io/post/comparing-go-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR &amp;ldquo;Java is to Javascript like Car is to Carpet.&amp;rdquo; - Collective Genius
My Computer Language is Better than Yours Some programming languages were - let&amp;rsquo;s say - discovered over time, whereas others were created academically by carefully selecting the features that would provide solutions to a set of problems. There’s nothing terribly new about spawning programming languages. However, haters gonna hate and will always find one, in an office near you or over the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>